<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Crow Data Science</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Crow Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling Salesman Problem in R with Location Data</title>
      <link>/travelling-salesman-problem-in-r-with-location-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/travelling-salesman-problem-in-r-with-location-data/</guid>
      <description>Being locked down gave me an idea:
If I could travel, whats the shortest distance to visit all Australian football grounds?
To answer this question, I’m going to be exploring one of the most famous optimisation problems in mathematics: the Traveling Salesman Problem, or a Travelling Footballer Problem.
The dataHere’s some data I prepared earlier, 17 venues with corresponding latitude and longitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering Fantasy Points: Frequentist Method with Generalised Linear Models</title>
      <link>/reverse-engineering-fantasy-points-frequentist-method-glm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reverse-engineering-fantasy-points-frequentist-method-glm/</guid>
      <description>Hypothetical Situation:Fantasy points (FP) are a black box algorithm: no one knows what calculations are made to generate points. It’s a closely guarded industry secret and they don’t want to release their methodology to the rest of the AFL analytics community. We work for a rival ratings company and have been tasked with reverse engineering their methods, finding out what values are assigned to specific stats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useless AFL Stats Dashboard</title>
      <link>/useless-afl-stats-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/useless-afl-stats-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>#main {display: inline;float: left;width: 1200px;}Glossary:
hq_1_g: Home Q1 Goalshq_1_b: Home Q1 Behindsaq_x_x: Awaypq_x_x: Playing foroq_x_x: Opposition</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new way of interpreting Brownlow Medal data</title>
      <link>/afl-brownlow-medal-votes-data-analysis-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/afl-brownlow-medal-votes-data-analysis-r/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe Brownlow medal, one of the most prestigious AFL awards, is notoriously difficult to predict. You can read this article from Fat Stats for a great look as to why. Here’s a quick summary:
Umpires are human and have their own biasesHighly predictive stats from last year may not be predictive this yearMedia influence may impact umpires when they voteAnother point that I’d like to throw into the mix:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to AFL Analytics with Useless AFL Stats</title>
      <link>/introduction-afl-analytics-data-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction-afl-analytics-data-r/</guid>
      <description>I’m co-admin of a little page on Facebook that caters to a niche audience of AFL statistics nerds known as Useless AFL Stats, where (founder and co-admin) Aaron and I discover stats that have no relevance to anything at all, and will never be useful to anyone, ever. And that got me thinking, why should I have all the fun finding these nuggets of gold?
I’m a firm believer in open source programming and data, the idea that as much data should be made publicly available as possible to the largest possible audience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>