<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Useless AFL Stats on Crow Data Science</title>
    <link>/tags/useless-afl-stats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Useless AFL Stats on Crow Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/useless-afl-stats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AFL Analytics with Useless AFL Stats - Part 2</title>
      <link>/afl-analytics-data-r-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/afl-analytics-data-r-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Part 2 of a beginners guide to AFL analytics and programming in R! This post will be following directly on from my first post, which you can access here. It covers the main points of installing R and RStudio and loading AFL data into your workspace.
If you have any questions during this tutorial, you can tweet at me @crow_data_sci. If you’ve got a useless stat, feel free to message at us Useless AFL Stats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useless AFL Stats Dashboard</title>
      <link>/useless-afl-stats-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/useless-afl-stats-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>#main {display: inline;float: left;width: 1200px;}Glossary:
hq_1_g: Home Q1 Goalshq_1_b: Home Q1 Behindsaq_x_x: Awaypq_x_x: Playing foroq_x_x: Opposition</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to AFL Analytics with Useless AFL Stats</title>
      <link>/introduction-afl-analytics-data-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction-afl-analytics-data-r/</guid>
      <description>I’m co-admin of a little page on Facebook that caters to a niche audience of AFL statistics nerds known as Useless AFL Stats, where (founder and co-admin) Aaron and I discover stats that have no relevance to anything at all, and will never be useful to anyone, ever. And that got me thinking, why should I have all the fun finding these nuggets of gold?
I’m a firm believer in open source programming and data, the idea that as much data should be made publicly available as possible to the largest possible audience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>